newswala.com 2015-11-01

# Privacy Policy - www.NewsWala.com

Please note, this privacy policy applies to this website or our mobile applications (for example our iPhone, android and iPad apps) (a "Site"). If you do not accept this privacy policy and cookies notice, do not use this Site. 

At www.newswala.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by www.newswala.com and how it is used. 

Information we may hold about you  
• Information you've provided to us, including our websites  
• Information about products and services you've ordered or enquired about  
• Information provided by other companies who have obtained your permission to share information about you  
• Information about your interaction with adverts and services such as registration, comments  
• Information we collect using cookies stored on your device (for example, this may be a PC, phone or tablet) about your use of Newswala.com and/or selected third party websites. For more information on cookies and how to manage them, please see our cookies notice below.   
• Your IP address, this is a number that identifies a specific network device on the internet and is required for your device and is required for your device to communicate with websites  
• Technical information from your device relating to the service you receive

Please do not submit your personal information to us if you do not wish us to collect it. 

Email a friend and share this article facilities 

Please note, when you use these facilities and provide us with personal data (e.g. the name and email address) of a third party, please ensure that you have their consent before giving us their details. 

How we may use your information 

By using this Site, you agree that we may collect, hold, process and use your information (including personal information) for the purpose of providing you with the Site services and developing our business which shall include (without limitation):

• Verifying your identity (for example when you return to the Site)  
• Personalising your visits to the Site and developing the design and style of the Site to improve the services provided to you  
• Informing you about the latest changes to the Site, or products, services or promotional offers that you might find interesting  
• Dealing with, and responding to you about, a comment you have submitted for or on our message boards, blogs and other such user generated content facilities  
• Enabling you to share our content with others e.g. using our Email a friend and Share this article facilities  
• Informing you if you have been successful in any Site competitions or promotions  
• Compiling customer reviews  
• Conducting market research  
• Carrying out statistical, technical and logistical analysis  
• According to your preferences, communicating (and personalising such communication) with you:  
• To send you periodic newsletters about your chosen services  
• To send you direct marketing. This may include communications by post, telephone or email or SMS about us and our business partners' products and services, events and special offers, including where applicable, for a reasonable time after you have ceased to be a reader of ours  
• To provide you with personalised services, such as providing with you with viewing recommendations and tailored advertising. This includes where we have agreement to store information about you on the devices you use, for example to make some of the adverts you see more relevant to you  
• To provide you with advertising more relevant to your interests and your online behaviour through the use of cookies when you visit our website(s)

We may share your personal information with other companies within our group of companies Subject to obtaining your consent, we may also supply personal information about you to third parties 

We may transfer, sell or assign any of the information described in this policy to third parties as a result of a sale, merger, consolidation, change of control, transfer of assets or reorganisation of our business. 

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at editor@newswala.com. 

**Log Files**

Like many other Web sites, www.newswala.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. 

**Cookies & 3rd Party Advertisements** We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp. **Cookies and Web Beacons**

www.newswala.com does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser. 

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on www.newswala.com.  
Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to www.newswala.com and other sites on the Internet.  
Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html 

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include Google Adsense 

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.newswala.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see. 

www.newswala.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. 

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. www.newswala.com's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. 

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites. 

**Safeguards and Security**

No data transmission over the internet can be entirely secure, so we do not guarantee the security of your personal information and/or use of the Site. However, we use reasonable endeavours to protect the security of your personal information from unauthorised access or use by using encryption technology. 

Contacting us and accessing your personal information Any queries or comments about this privacy notice or if you wish to review or receive copies of the personal information we hold about you should be sent to editor@newswala.com or write to us at: 

**Legal Department  
The Hyderabad Deccan (English Daily)  
# 16-8-238/7/A, Ground Floor, Ashraf Nagar  
New Malakpet, Hyderabad-500024. A.P(India)  
Off:009140 24522222 Fax:009140 24521111  
email: editor@newswala.com  
**
